<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<ValueSet xmlns="http://hl7.org/fhir">
  <id value="R5-v3-ActInformationSensitivityPolicy-for-R4"/>
  <language value="en"/>
  <text>
    <status value="generated"/><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p class="res-header-id"><b>Generated Narrative: ValueSet R5-v3-ActInformationSensitivityPolicy-for-R4</b></p><a name="R5-v3-ActInformationSensitivityPolicy-for-R4"> </a><a name="hcR5-v3-ActInformationSensitivityPolicy-for-R4"> </a><p>This value set expansion contains 25 concepts.</p><table class="codes"><tr><td><b>System</b></td><td><b>Version</b></td><td style="white-space:nowrap"><b>Code</b></td><td><b>Display</b></td><td><b>Definition</b></td></tr><tr><td><a name="R5-v3-ActInformationSensitivityPolicy-for-R4-http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode-BH"> </a><code>http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode</code></td><td>8.0.0</td><td style="white-space:nowrap">  <a href="CodeSystem-v3-ActCode.html#v3-ActCode-BH">BH</a></td><td>behavioral health information sensitivity</td><td><div><p>Policy for handling information related to behavioral and emotional disturbances affecting social adjustment and physical health, which is afforded heightened confidentiality.</p>
<p><em>Usage Note:</em> If there is a jurisdictional mandate, then use the applicable ActPrivacyLaw code system, and specify the law in addition to this more generic code.</p>
</div></td></tr><tr><td><a name="R5-v3-ActInformationSensitivityPolicy-for-R4-http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode-COGN"> </a><code>http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode</code></td><td>8.0.0</td><td style="white-space:nowrap">  <a href="CodeSystem-v3-ActCode.html#v3-ActCode-COGN">COGN</a></td><td>cognitive disability information sensitivity</td><td><div><p>Policy for handling information related to cognitive disability disorders and conditions caused by these disorders, which are afforded heightened confidentiality.</p>
<p><em>Usage Note:</em> If there is a jurisdictional mandate, then use the applicable ActPrivacyLaw code system, and specify the law in addition to this more generic code.</p>
<p>Examples may include dementia, traumatic brain injury, attention deficit, hearing and visual disability such as dyslexia and other disorders and related conditions which impair learning and self-sufficiency. However, the cognitive disabilities to which this term may apply versus other behavioral health categories varies by jurisdiction and organizational policy in part due to overlap with other behavioral health conditions. Implementers should constrain to those diagnoses applicable in the domain in which this code is used.</p>
</div></td></tr><tr><td><a name="R5-v3-ActInformationSensitivityPolicy-for-R4-http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode-DVD"> </a><code>http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode</code></td><td>8.0.0</td><td style="white-space:nowrap">  <a href="CodeSystem-v3-ActCode.html#v3-ActCode-DVD">DVD</a></td><td>developmental disability information sensitivity</td><td><div><p>Policy for handling information related to developmental disability disorders and conditions caused by these disorders, which is afforded heightened confidentiality.</p>
<p><em>Usage Note:</em> If there is a jurisdictional mandate, then use the applicable ActPrivacyLaw code system, and specify the law in addition to this more generic code.</p>
<p>A diverse group of chronic conditions that are due to mental or physical impairments impacting activities of daily living, self-care, language acuity, learning, mobility, independent living and economic self-sufficiency. Examples may include Down syndrome and Autism spectrum. However, the developmental disabilities to which this term applies versus other behavioral health categories varies by jurisdiction and organizational policy in part due to overlap with other behavioral health conditions. Implementers should constrain to those diagnoses applicable in the domain in which this code is used.</p>
</div></td></tr><tr><td><a name="R5-v3-ActInformationSensitivityPolicy-for-R4-http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode-EMOTDIS"> </a><code>http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode</code></td><td>8.0.0</td><td style="white-space:nowrap">  <a href="CodeSystem-v3-ActCode.html#v3-ActCode-EMOTDIS">EMOTDIS</a></td><td>emotional disturbance information sensitivity</td><td><div><p>Policy for handling information related to emotional disturbance disorders and conditions caused by these disorders, which is afforded heightened confidentiality.</p>
<p><em>Usage Note:</em> If there is a jurisdictional mandate, then use the applicable ActPrivacyLaw code system, and specify the law in addition to this more generic code.</p>
<p>Typical used to characterize behavioral and mental health issues of adolescents where the disorder may be temporarily diagnosed in order to avoid the potential and unnecessary stigmatizing diagnoses of disorder long term.</p>
</div></td></tr><tr><td><a name="R5-v3-ActInformationSensitivityPolicy-for-R4-http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode-ETH"> </a><code>http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode</code></td><td>8.0.0</td><td style="white-space:nowrap">  <a href="CodeSystem-v3-ActCode.html#v3-ActCode-ETH">ETH</a></td><td>substance abuse information sensitivity</td><td><div><p>Policy for handling alcohol or drug-abuse information, which will be afforded heightened confidentiality. Information handling protocols based on organizational policies related to alcohol or drug-abuse information that is deemed sensitive.</p>
<p><em>Usage Note:</em> If there is a jurisdictional mandate, then use the applicable ActPrivacyLaw code system, and specify the law rather than or in addition to this more generic code.</p>
</div></td></tr><tr><td><a name="R5-v3-ActInformationSensitivityPolicy-for-R4-http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode-ETHUD"> </a><code>http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode</code></td><td>8.0.0</td><td style="white-space:nowrap">  <a href="CodeSystem-v3-ActCode.html#v3-ActCode-ETHUD">ETHUD</a></td><td>alcohol use disorder information sensitivity</td><td><div><p>Policy for handling information related to alcohol use disorders and conditions caused by these disorders, which is afforded heightened confidentiality.</p>
<p><em>Usage Note:</em> If there is a jurisdictional mandate, then use the applicable ActPrivacyLaw code system, and specify the law in addition to this more generic code.</p>
</div></td></tr><tr><td><a name="R5-v3-ActInformationSensitivityPolicy-for-R4-http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode-GDIS"> </a><code>http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode</code></td><td>8.0.0</td><td style="white-space:nowrap">  <a href="CodeSystem-v3-ActCode.html#v3-ActCode-GDIS">GDIS</a></td><td>genetic disease information sensitivity</td><td><div><p>Policy for handling genetic disease information, which will be afforded heightened confidentiality. Information handling protocols based on organizational policies related to genetic disease information that is deemed sensitive.</p>
<p><em>Usage Note:</em> If there is a jurisdictional mandate, then use the applicable ActPrivacyLaw code system, and specify the law rather than or in addition to this more generic code.</p>
</div></td></tr><tr><td><a name="R5-v3-ActInformationSensitivityPolicy-for-R4-http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode-HIV"> </a><code>http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode</code></td><td>8.0.0</td><td style="white-space:nowrap">  <a href="CodeSystem-v3-ActCode.html#v3-ActCode-HIV">HIV</a></td><td>HIV/AIDS information sensitivity</td><td><div><p>Policy for handling HIV or AIDS information, which will be afforded heightened confidentiality. Information handling protocols based on organizational policies related to HIV or AIDS information that is deemed sensitive.</p>
<p><em>Usage Note:</em> If there is a jurisdictional mandate, then use the applicable ActPrivacyLaw code system, and specify the law rather than or in addition to this more generic code.</p>
</div></td></tr><tr><td><a name="R5-v3-ActInformationSensitivityPolicy-for-R4-http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode-IDS"> </a><code>http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode</code></td><td>8.0.0</td><td style="white-space:nowrap">  <a href="CodeSystem-v3-ActCode.html#v3-ActCode-IDS">IDS</a></td><td>Identifier Sensitivity</td><td><div><p>Policy for handling information related to an identifier of an information subject, which will be afforded heightened confidentiality. Usage Note: Such policies may govern the sensitivity of information related to an identifier of an act, such as the identifier of a contract; a role, such as a citizen, a patient, a practitioner, or an organization; or an entity such as a medical device due to potential impact on the privacy, well-being, safety or integrity of an information subject. For example, protection against identity fraud or counterfeit.</p>
</div></td></tr><tr><td><a name="R5-v3-ActInformationSensitivityPolicy-for-R4-http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode-MH"> </a><code>http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode</code></td><td>8.0.0</td><td style="white-space:nowrap">  <a href="CodeSystem-v3-ActCode.html#v3-ActCode-MH">MH</a></td><td>mental health information sensitivity</td><td><div><p>Policy for handling information related to psychological disorders, which is afforded heightened confidentiality. Mental health information may be deemed specifically sensitive and distinct from physical health, substance use disorders, and behavioral disabilities and disorders in some jurisdictions.</p>
<p><em>Usage Note:</em> If there is a jurisdictional mandate, then use the applicable ActPrivacyLaw code system, and specify the law in addition to this more generic code.</p>
</div></td></tr><tr><td><a name="R5-v3-ActInformationSensitivityPolicy-for-R4-http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode-MST"> </a><code>http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode</code></td><td>8.0.0</td><td style="white-space:nowrap">  <a href="CodeSystem-v3-ActCode.html#v3-ActCode-MST">MST</a></td><td>military sexual trauma information sensitivity</td><td><div><p>Policy for handling information related to sexual assault or repeated, threatening sexual harassment that occurred while the patient was in the military, which is afforded heightened confidentiality.</p>
<p>Access control concerns for military sexual trauma is based on the patient being subject to control by a higher ranking military perpetrator and/or censure by others within the military unit. Due to the relatively unfettered access to healthcare information by higher ranking military personnel and those who have command over the patient, there is a need to sequester this information outside of the typical controls on access to military health records.</p>
<p><em>Usage Note:</em> If there is a jurisdictional mandate, then use the applicable ActPrivacyLaw code system, and specify the law in addition to this more generic code.</p>
</div></td></tr><tr><td><a name="R5-v3-ActInformationSensitivityPolicy-for-R4-http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode-OPIOIDUD"> </a><code>http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode</code></td><td>8.0.0</td><td style="white-space:nowrap">  <a href="CodeSystem-v3-ActCode.html#v3-ActCode-OPIOIDUD">OPIOIDUD</a></td><td>opioid use disorder information sensitivity</td><td><div><p>Policy for handling information related to opioid use disorders and conditions caused by these disorders, which is afforded heightened confidentiality.</p>
<p><em>Usage Note:</em> If there is a jurisdictional mandate, then use the applicable ActPrivacyLaw code system, and specify the law in addition to this more generic code.</p>
</div></td></tr><tr><td><a name="R5-v3-ActInformationSensitivityPolicy-for-R4-http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode-PREGNANT"> </a><code>http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode</code></td><td>8.0.0</td><td style="white-space:nowrap">  <a href="CodeSystem-v3-ActCode.html#v3-ActCode-PREGNANT">PREGNANT</a></td><td>pregnancy information sensitivity</td><td><div><p>Policy for handling information about an individual's current or past pregnancy status, deemed sensitive by the individual or by policy, which may be afforded heightened confidentiality.</p>
<p><em>Usage Note:</em></p>
<p>Information about a patient's current or past pregnancy status may be considered sensitive in circumstances in which that status could result in discrimination or stigmatization.</p>
</div></td></tr><tr><td><a name="R5-v3-ActInformationSensitivityPolicy-for-R4-http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode-PSY"> </a><code>http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode</code></td><td>8.0.0</td><td style="white-space:nowrap">  <a href="CodeSystem-v3-ActCode.html#v3-ActCode-PSY">PSY</a></td><td>psychiatry disorder information sensitivity</td><td><div><p>Policy for handling psychiatry psychiatric disorder information, which is afforded heightened confidentiality.</p>
<p><em>Usage Note:</em> If there is a jurisdictional mandate, then use the applicable ActPrivacyLaw code system, and specify the law rather than or in addition to this more generic code.</p>
</div></td></tr><tr><td><a name="R5-v3-ActInformationSensitivityPolicy-for-R4-http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode-PSYTHPN"> </a><code>http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode</code></td><td>8.0.0</td><td style="white-space:nowrap">  <a href="CodeSystem-v3-ActCode.html#v3-ActCode-PSYTHPN">PSYTHPN</a></td><td>psychotherapy note information sensitivity</td><td><div><p>Policy for handling psychotherapy note information, which is afforded heightened confidentiality.</p>
<p><em>Usage Note:</em> In some jurisdiction, disclosure of psychotherapy notes requires patient consent.</p>
<p>If there is a jurisdictional mandate, then use the applicable ActPrivacyLaw code system, and specify the law rather than or in addition to this more generic code.</p>
</div></td></tr><tr><td><a name="R5-v3-ActInformationSensitivityPolicy-for-R4-http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode-SCA"> </a><code>http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode</code></td><td>8.0.0</td><td style="white-space:nowrap">  <a href="CodeSystem-v3-ActCode.html#v3-ActCode-SCA">SCA</a></td><td>sickle cell anemia information sensitivity</td><td><div><p>Policy for handling sickle cell disease information, which is afforded heightened confidentiality. Information handling protocols are based on organizational policies related to sickle cell disease information, which is deemed sensitive.</p>
<p><em>Usage Note:</em> If there is a jurisdictional mandate, then the Act valued with this ActCode should be associated with an Act valued with any applicable laws from the ActPrivacyLaw code system.</p>
</div></td></tr><tr><td><a name="R5-v3-ActInformationSensitivityPolicy-for-R4-http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode-SDV"> </a><code>http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode</code></td><td>8.0.0</td><td style="white-space:nowrap">  <a href="CodeSystem-v3-ActCode.html#v3-ActCode-SDV">SDV</a></td><td>sexual assault, abuse, or domestic violence information sensitivity</td><td><div><p>Policy for handling sexual assault, abuse, or domestic violence information, which will be afforded heightened confidentiality. Information handling protocols based on organizational policies related to sexual assault, abuse, or domestic violence information that is deemed sensitive.</p>
<p>SDV code covers violence perpetrated by related and non-related persons. This code should be specific to physical and mental trauma caused by a related person only. The access control concerns are keeping the patient safe from the perpetrator who may have an abusive psychological control over the patient, may be stalking the patient, or may try to manipulate care givers into allowing the perpetrator to make contact with the patient. The definition needs to be clarified.</p>
<p><em>Usage Note:</em> If there is a jurisdictional mandate, then use the applicable ActPrivacyLaw code system, and specify the law rather than or in addition to this more generic code.</p>
</div></td></tr><tr><td><a name="R5-v3-ActInformationSensitivityPolicy-for-R4-http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode-SEX"> </a><code>http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode</code></td><td>8.0.0</td><td style="white-space:nowrap">  <a href="CodeSystem-v3-ActCode.html#v3-ActCode-SEX">SEX</a></td><td>sexuality and reproductive health information sensitivity</td><td><div><p>Policy for handling sexuality and reproductive health information, which will be afforded heightened confidentiality. Information handling protocols based on organizational policies related to sexuality and reproductive health information that is deemed sensitive.</p>
<p><em>Usage Note:</em> If there is a jurisdictional mandate, then use the applicable ActPrivacyLaw code system, and specify the law rather than or in addition to this more generic code.</p>
</div></td></tr><tr><td><a name="R5-v3-ActInformationSensitivityPolicy-for-R4-http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode-SICKLE"> </a><code>http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode</code></td><td>8.0.0</td><td style="white-space:nowrap">  <a href="CodeSystem-v3-ActCode.html#v3-ActCode-SICKLE">SICKLE</a></td><td>sickle cell</td><td><div><p>Types of sensitivity policies that apply to Acts. Act.confidentialityCode is defined in the RIM as &quot;constraints around appropriate disclosure of information about this Act, regardless of mood.&quot;</p>
<p><em>Usage Note:</em> ActSensitivity codes are used to bind information to an Act.confidentialityCode according to local sensitivity policy so that those confidentiality codes can then govern its handling across enterprises. Internally to a policy domain, however, local policies guide the access control system on how end users in that policy domain are able to use information tagged with these sensitivity values.</p>
</div></td></tr><tr><td><a name="R5-v3-ActInformationSensitivityPolicy-for-R4-http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode-SPI"> </a><code>http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode</code></td><td>8.0.0</td><td style="white-space:nowrap">  <a href="CodeSystem-v3-ActCode.html#v3-ActCode-SPI">SPI</a></td><td>specially protected information sensitivity</td><td><div><p>Policy for handling information deemed specially protected by law or policy including substance abuse, substance use, psychiatric, mental health, behavioral health, and cognitive disorders, which is afforded heightened confidentiality.</p>
<p><em>Usage Note:</em> If there is a jurisdictional mandate, then use the applicable ActPrivacyLaw code system, and specify the law in addition to this more generic code.</p>
</div></td></tr><tr><td><a name="R5-v3-ActInformationSensitivityPolicy-for-R4-http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode-STD"> </a><code>http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode</code></td><td>8.0.0</td><td style="white-space:nowrap">  <a href="CodeSystem-v3-ActCode.html#v3-ActCode-STD">STD</a></td><td>sexually transmitted disease information sensitivity</td><td><div><p>Policy for handling sexually transmitted disease information, which will be afforded heightened confidentiality. Information handling protocols based on organizational policies related to sexually transmitted disease information that is deemed sensitive.</p>
<p><em>Usage Note:</em> If there is a jurisdictional mandate, then use the applicable ActPrivacyLaw code system, and specify the law rather than or in addition to this more generic code.</p>
</div></td></tr><tr><td><a name="R5-v3-ActInformationSensitivityPolicy-for-R4-http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode-SUD"> </a><code>http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode</code></td><td>8.0.0</td><td style="white-space:nowrap">  <a href="CodeSystem-v3-ActCode.html#v3-ActCode-SUD">SUD</a></td><td>substance use disorder information sensitivity</td><td><div><p>Policy for handling information related to alcohol or drug use disorders and conditions caused by these disorders, which is afforded heightened confidentiality.</p>
<p><em>Usage Note:</em> If there is a jurisdictional mandate, then use the applicable ActPrivacyLaw code system, and specify the law in addition to this more generic code.</p>
</div></td></tr><tr><td><a name="R5-v3-ActInformationSensitivityPolicy-for-R4-http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode-TBOO"> </a><code>http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode</code></td><td>8.0.0</td><td style="white-space:nowrap">  <a href="CodeSystem-v3-ActCode.html#v3-ActCode-TBOO">TBOO</a></td><td>taboo</td><td><div><p>Policy for handling information not to be initially disclosed or discussed with patient except by a physician assigned to patient in this case. Information handling protocols based on organizational policies related to sensitive patient information that must be initially discussed with the patient by an attending physician before being disclosed to the patient.</p>
<p><em>Usage Note:</em> If there is a jurisdictional mandate, then use the applicable ActPrivacyLaw code system, and specify the law rather than or in addition to this more generic code.</p>
<p><em>Open Issue:</em> This definition conflates a rule and a characteristic, and there may be a similar issue with ts sibling codes.</p>
</div></td></tr><tr><td><a name="R5-v3-ActInformationSensitivityPolicy-for-R4-http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode-VIO"> </a><code>http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode</code></td><td>8.0.0</td><td style="white-space:nowrap">  <a href="CodeSystem-v3-ActCode.html#v3-ActCode-VIO">VIO</a></td><td>violence information sensitivity</td><td><div><p>Policy for handling information related to harm by violence, which is afforded heightened confidentiality. Harm by violence is perpetrated by an unrelated person.</p>
<p>Access control concerns for information about mental or physical harm resulting from violence caused by an unrelated person may include manipulation of care givers or access to records that enable the perpetrator contact or locate the patient, but the perpetrator will likely not have established abusive psychological control over the patient.</p>
<p><em>Usage Note:</em> If there is a jurisdictional mandate, then use the applicable ActPrivacyLaw code system, and specify the law in addition to this more generic code.</p>
</div></td></tr><tr><td><a name="R5-v3-ActInformationSensitivityPolicy-for-R4-http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode-_ActInformationSensitivityPolicy"> </a><code>http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode</code></td><td>8.0.0</td><td style="white-space:nowrap">  <a href="CodeSystem-v3-ActCode.html#v3-ActCode-_ActInformationSensitivityPolicy">_ActInformationSensitivityPolicy</a></td><td>ActInformationSensitivityPolicy</td><td><div><p>Types of sensitivity policies that apply to Acts. Act.confidentialityCode is defined in the RIM as &quot;constraints around appropriate disclosure of information about this Act, regardless of mood.&quot;</p>
<p><em>Usage Note:</em> ActSensitivity codes are used to bind information to an Act.confidentialityCode according to local sensitivity policy so that those confidentiality codes can then govern its handling across enterprises. Internally to a policy domain, however, local policies guide the access control system on how end users in that policy domain are able to use information tagged with these sensitivity values.</p>
</div></td></tr></table></div>
  </text>
  <extension url="http://hl7.org/fhir/StructureDefinition/structuredefinition-wg">
    <valueCode value="fhir"/>
  </extension>
  <extension url="http://hl7.org/fhir/StructureDefinition/package-source">
    <extension url="packageId">
      <valueId value="hl7.fhir.uv.xver-r5.r4"/>
    </extension>
    <extension url="version">
      <valueString value="0.0.1-snapshot-3"/>
    </extension>
    <extension url="uri">
      <valueUri value="http://hl7.org/fhir/uv/xver/ImplementationGuide/hl7.fhir.uv.xver-r5.r4"/>
    </extension>
  </extension>
  <extension url="http://hl7.org/fhir/StructureDefinition/structuredefinition-fmm">
    <valueInteger value="0">
      <extension url="http://hl7.org/fhir/StructureDefinition/structuredefinition-conformance-derivedFrom">
        <valueCanonical value="http://hl7.org/fhir/uv/xver/ImplementationGuide/hl7.fhir.uv.xver-r5.r4"/>
      </extension>
    </valueInteger>
  </extension>
  <extension url="http://hl7.org/fhir/StructureDefinition/structuredefinition-standards-status">
    <valueCode value="trial-use">
      <extension url="http://hl7.org/fhir/StructureDefinition/structuredefinition-conformance-derivedFrom">
        <valueCanonical value="http://hl7.org/fhir/uv/xver/ImplementationGuide/hl7.fhir.uv.xver-r5.r4"/>
      </extension>
    </valueCode>
  </extension>
  <url value="http://hl7.org/fhir/uv/xver/ValueSet/R5-v3-ActInformationSensitivityPolicy-for-R4"/>
  <version value="0.0.1-snapshot-3"/>
  <name value="R5V3ActInformationSensitivityPolicyForR4"/>
  <title value="Cross-version ValueSet R5.ActInformationSensitivityPolicy for use in FHIR R4"/>
  <status value="active"/>
  <experimental value="false"/>
  <date value="2026-02-21T19:36:42.9229177+00:00"/>
  <publisher value="FHIR Infrastructure"/>
  <contact>
    <name value="FHIR Infrastructure"/>
    <telecom>
      <system value="url"/>
      <value value="http://www.hl7.org/Special/committees/fiwg"/>
    </telecom>
  </contact>
  <description value="This cross-version ValueSet represents content from `http://terminology.hl7.org/ValueSet/v3-ActInformationSensitivityPolicy|2.0.0` for use in FHIR R4."/>
  <jurisdiction>
    <coding>
      <system value="http://unstats.un.org/unsd/methods/m49/m49.htm"/>
      <code value="001"/>
      <display value="World"/>
    </coding>
  </jurisdiction>
  <purpose value="This value set is part of the cross-version definitions generated to enable use of the&#xD;&#xA;value set `http://terminology.hl7.org/ValueSet/v3-ActInformationSensitivityPolicy|2.0.0` as defined in FHIR R5&#xD;&#xA;in FHIR R4.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;The source value set is bound to the following FHIR R5 elements:&#xD;&#xA;* &#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;The following concepts are not included in this cross-version definition because they have valid representations&#xD;&#xA;* _no concepts_&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;Following are the generation technical comments:&#xD;&#xA;&#xA;FHIR ValueSet `http://terminology.hl7.org/ValueSet/v3-ActInformationSensitivityPolicy|2.0.0`, defined in FHIR R5 does not have any mapping to FHIR R4"/>
  <compose>
    <include>
      <system value="http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode"/>
      <version value="8.0.0"/>
      <concept>
        <code value="BH"/>
        <display value="behavioral health information sensitivity"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="COGN"/>
        <display value="cognitive disability information sensitivity"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="DVD"/>
        <display value="developmental disability information sensitivity"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="EMOTDIS"/>
        <display value="emotional disturbance information sensitivity"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="ETH"/>
        <display value="substance abuse information sensitivity"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="ETHUD"/>
        <display value="alcohol use disorder information sensitivity"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="GDIS"/>
        <display value="genetic disease information sensitivity"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="HIV"/>
        <display value="HIV/AIDS information sensitivity"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="IDS"/>
        <display value="Identifier Sensitivity"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="MH"/>
        <display value="mental health information sensitivity"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="MST"/>
        <display value="military sexual trauma information sensitivity"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="OPIOIDUD"/>
        <display value="opioid use disorder information sensitivity"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="PREGNANT"/>
        <display value="pregnancy information sensitivity"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="PSY"/>
        <display value="psychiatry disorder information sensitivity"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="PSYTHPN"/>
        <display value="psychotherapy note information sensitivity"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="SCA"/>
        <display value="sickle cell anemia information sensitivity"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="SDV"/>
        <display value="sexual assault, abuse, or domestic violence information sensitivity"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="SEX"/>
        <display value="sexuality and reproductive health information sensitivity"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="SICKLE"/>
        <display value="sickle cell"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="SPI"/>
        <display value="specially protected information sensitivity"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="STD"/>
        <display value="sexually transmitted disease information sensitivity"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="SUD"/>
        <display value="substance use disorder information sensitivity"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="TBOO"/>
        <display value="taboo"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="VIO"/>
        <display value="violence information sensitivity"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="_ActInformationSensitivityPolicy"/>
        <display value="ActInformationSensitivityPolicy"/>
      </concept>
    </include>
  </compose>
  <expansion>
    <timestamp value="2026-02-21T19:36:42.9229177+00:00"/>
    <contains>
      <system value="http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode"/>
      <version value="8.0.0"/>
      <code value="BH"/>
      <display value="behavioral health information sensitivity"/>
    </contains>
    <contains>
      <system value="http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode"/>
      <version value="8.0.0"/>
      <code value="COGN"/>
      <display value="cognitive disability information sensitivity"/>
    </contains>
    <contains>
      <system value="http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode"/>
      <version value="8.0.0"/>
      <code value="DVD"/>
      <display value="developmental disability information sensitivity"/>
    </contains>
    <contains>
      <system value="http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode"/>
      <version value="8.0.0"/>
      <code value="EMOTDIS"/>
      <display value="emotional disturbance information sensitivity"/>
    </contains>
    <contains>
      <system value="http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode"/>
      <version value="8.0.0"/>
      <code value="ETH"/>
      <display value="substance abuse information sensitivity"/>
    </contains>
    <contains>
      <system value="http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode"/>
      <version value="8.0.0"/>
      <code value="ETHUD"/>
      <display value="alcohol use disorder information sensitivity"/>
    </contains>
    <contains>
      <system value="http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode"/>
      <version value="8.0.0"/>
      <code value="GDIS"/>
      <display value="genetic disease information sensitivity"/>
    </contains>
    <contains>
      <system value="http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode"/>
      <version value="8.0.0"/>
      <code value="HIV"/>
      <display value="HIV/AIDS information sensitivity"/>
    </contains>
    <contains>
      <system value="http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode"/>
      <version value="8.0.0"/>
      <code value="IDS"/>
      <display value="Identifier Sensitivity"/>
    </contains>
    <contains>
      <system value="http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode"/>
      <version value="8.0.0"/>
      <code value="MH"/>
      <display value="mental health information sensitivity"/>
    </contains>
    <contains>
      <system value="http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode"/>
      <version value="8.0.0"/>
      <code value="MST"/>
      <display value="military sexual trauma information sensitivity"/>
    </contains>
    <contains>
      <system value="http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode"/>
      <version value="8.0.0"/>
      <code value="OPIOIDUD"/>
      <display value="opioid use disorder information sensitivity"/>
    </contains>
    <contains>
      <system value="http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode"/>
      <version value="8.0.0"/>
      <code value="PREGNANT"/>
      <display value="pregnancy information sensitivity"/>
    </contains>
    <contains>
      <system value="http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode"/>
      <version value="8.0.0"/>
      <code value="PSY"/>
      <display value="psychiatry disorder information sensitivity"/>
    </contains>
    <contains>
      <system value="http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode"/>
      <version value="8.0.0"/>
      <code value="PSYTHPN"/>
      <display value="psychotherapy note information sensitivity"/>
    </contains>
    <contains>
      <system value="http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode"/>
      <version value="8.0.0"/>
      <code value="SCA"/>
      <display value="sickle cell anemia information sensitivity"/>
    </contains>
    <contains>
      <system value="http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode"/>
      <version value="8.0.0"/>
      <code value="SDV"/>
      <display value="sexual assault, abuse, or domestic violence information sensitivity"/>
    </contains>
    <contains>
      <system value="http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode"/>
      <version value="8.0.0"/>
      <code value="SEX"/>
      <display value="sexuality and reproductive health information sensitivity"/>
    </contains>
    <contains>
      <system value="http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode"/>
      <version value="8.0.0"/>
      <code value="SICKLE"/>
      <display value="sickle cell"/>
    </contains>
    <contains>
      <system value="http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode"/>
      <version value="8.0.0"/>
      <code value="SPI"/>
      <display value="specially protected information sensitivity"/>
    </contains>
    <contains>
      <system value="http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode"/>
      <version value="8.0.0"/>
      <code value="STD"/>
      <display value="sexually transmitted disease information sensitivity"/>
    </contains>
    <contains>
      <system value="http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode"/>
      <version value="8.0.0"/>
      <code value="SUD"/>
      <display value="substance use disorder information sensitivity"/>
    </contains>
    <contains>
      <system value="http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode"/>
      <version value="8.0.0"/>
      <code value="TBOO"/>
      <display value="taboo"/>
    </contains>
    <contains>
      <system value="http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode"/>
      <version value="8.0.0"/>
      <code value="VIO"/>
      <display value="violence information sensitivity"/>
    </contains>
    <contains>
      <system value="http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode"/>
      <version value="8.0.0"/>
      <code value="_ActInformationSensitivityPolicy"/>
      <display value="ActInformationSensitivityPolicy"/>
    </contains>
  </expansion>
</ValueSet>