<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<ValueSet xmlns="http://hl7.org/fhir">
  <id value="R5-v3-ActProgramTypeCode-for-R4"/>
  <text>
    <status value="generated"/><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p class="res-header-id"><b>Generated Narrative: ValueSet R5-v3-ActProgramTypeCode-for-R4</b></p><a name="R5-v3-ActProgramTypeCode-for-R4"> </a><a name="hcR5-v3-ActProgramTypeCode-for-R4"> </a><p>This value set expansion contains 25 concepts.</p><table class="codes"><tr><td><b>System</b></td><td><b>Version</b></td><td style="white-space:nowrap"><b>Code</b></td><td><b>Display</b></td><td><b>Definition</b></td></tr><tr><td><a name="R5-v3-ActProgramTypeCode-for-R4-http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode-CANPRG"> </a><code>http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode</code></td><td>8.0.0</td><td style="white-space:nowrap">  <a href="CodeSystem-v3-ActCode.html#v3-ActCode-CANPRG">CANPRG</a></td><td>women's cancer detection program</td><td><div><p><strong>Definition:</strong> A program that provides low-income, uninsured, and underserved women access to timely, high-quality screening and diagnostic services, to detect breast and cervical cancer at the earliest stages.</p>
<p><strong>Example:</strong> To improve women's access to screening for breast and cervical cancers, Congress passed the Breast and Cervical Cancer Mortality Prevention Act of 1990, which guided CDC in creating the National Breast and Cervical Cancer Early Detection Program (NBCCEDP), which provides access to critical breast and cervical cancer screening services for underserved women in the United States. An estimated 7 to 10% of U.S. women of screening age are eligible to receive NBCCEDP services. Federal guidelines establish an eligibility baseline to direct services to uninsured and underinsured women at or below 250% of federal poverty level; ages 18 to 64 for cervical screening; ages 40 to 64 for breast screening.</p>
</div></td></tr><tr><td><a name="R5-v3-ActProgramTypeCode-for-R4-http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode-CHAR"> </a><code>http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode</code></td><td>8.0.0</td><td style="white-space:nowrap">  <a href="CodeSystem-v3-ActCode.html#v3-ActCode-CHAR">CHAR</a></td><td>charity program</td><td><div><p><strong>Definition:</strong> A program that covers the cost of services provided directly to a beneficiary who typically has no other source of coverage without charge.</p>
</div></td></tr><tr><td><a name="R5-v3-ActProgramTypeCode-for-R4-http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode-CRIME"> </a><code>http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode</code></td><td>8.0.0</td><td style="white-space:nowrap">  <a href="CodeSystem-v3-ActCode.html#v3-ActCode-CRIME">CRIME</a></td><td>crime victim program</td><td><div><p><strong>Definition:</strong> A program that covers the cost of services provided to crime victims for injuries or losses related to the occurrence of a crime.</p>
</div></td></tr><tr><td><a name="R5-v3-ActProgramTypeCode-for-R4-http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode-DENTPRG"> </a><code>http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode</code></td><td>8.0.0</td><td style="white-space:nowrap">  <a href="CodeSystem-v3-ActCode.html#v3-ActCode-DENTPRG">DENTPRG</a></td><td>dental program</td><td><div><p><strong>Definition:</strong> A public or government health program that administers and funds coverage for dental care to assist program eligible who meet financial and health status criteria.</p>
</div></td></tr><tr><td><a name="R5-v3-ActProgramTypeCode-for-R4-http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode-DISEASEPRG"> </a><code>http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode</code></td><td>8.0.0</td><td style="white-space:nowrap">  <a href="CodeSystem-v3-ActCode.html#v3-ActCode-DISEASEPRG">DISEASEPRG</a></td><td>public health program</td><td><div><p><strong>Definition:</strong> A public or government health program that administers and funds coverage for health and social services to assist program eligible who meet financial and health status criteria related to a particular disease.</p>
<p><strong>Example:</strong> Reproductive health, sexually transmitted disease, and end renal disease programs.</p>
</div></td></tr><tr><td><a name="R5-v3-ActProgramTypeCode-for-R4-http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode-EAP"> </a><code>http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode</code></td><td>8.0.0</td><td style="white-space:nowrap">  <a href="CodeSystem-v3-ActCode.html#v3-ActCode-EAP">EAP</a></td><td>employee assistance program</td><td><div><p><strong>Definition:</strong> An employee assistance program is run by an employer or employee organization for the purpose of providing benefits and covering all or part of the cost for employees to receive counseling, referrals, and advice in dealing with stressful issues in their lives. These may include substance abuse, bereavement, marital problems, weight issues, or general wellness issues. The services are usually provided by a third-party, rather than the company itself, and the company receives only summary statistical data from the service provider. Employee's names and services received are kept confidential.</p>
</div></td></tr><tr><td><a name="R5-v3-ActProgramTypeCode-for-R4-http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode-ENDRENAL"> </a><code>http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode</code></td><td>8.0.0</td><td style="white-space:nowrap">  <a href="CodeSystem-v3-ActCode.html#v3-ActCode-ENDRENAL">ENDRENAL</a></td><td>end renal program</td><td><div><p><strong>Definition:</strong> A public or government program that administers publicly funded coverage of kidney dialysis and kidney transplant services.</p>
<p>Example: In the U.S., the Medicare End-stage Renal Disease program (ESRD), the National Kidney Foundation (NKF) American Kidney Fund (AKF) The Organ Transplant Fund.</p>
</div></td></tr><tr><td><a name="R5-v3-ActProgramTypeCode-for-R4-http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode-GOVEMP"> </a><code>http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode</code></td><td>8.0.0</td><td style="white-space:nowrap">  <a href="CodeSystem-v3-ActCode.html#v3-ActCode-GOVEMP">GOVEMP</a></td><td>government employee health program</td><td><div><p><strong>Definition:</strong> A set of codes used to indicate a government program that is an organized structure for administering and funding coverage of a benefit package for covered parties meeting eligibility criteria, typically related to employment, health and financial status. Government programs are established or permitted by legislation with provisions for ongoing government oversight. Regulation mandates the structure of the program, the manner in which it is funded and administered, covered benefits, provider types, eligibility criteria and financial participation. A government agency is charged with implementing the program in accordance to the regulation</p>
<p><strong>Example:</strong> Federal employee health benefit program in the U.S.</p>
</div></td></tr><tr><td><a name="R5-v3-ActProgramTypeCode-for-R4-http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode-HIRISK"> </a><code>http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode</code></td><td>8.0.0</td><td style="white-space:nowrap">  <a href="CodeSystem-v3-ActCode.html#v3-ActCode-HIRISK">HIRISK</a></td><td>high risk pool program</td><td><div><p><strong>Definition:</strong> A government program that provides health coverage to individuals who are considered medically uninsurable or high risk, and who have been denied health insurance due to a serious health condition. In certain cases, it also applies to those who have been quoted very high premiums a&quot; again, due to a serious health condition. The pool charges premiums for coverage. Because the pool covers high-risk people, it incurs a higher level of claims than premiums can cover. The insurance industry pays into the pool to make up the difference and help it remain viable.</p>
</div></td></tr><tr><td><a name="R5-v3-ActProgramTypeCode-for-R4-http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode-HIVAIDS"> </a><code>http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode</code></td><td>8.0.0</td><td style="white-space:nowrap">  <a href="CodeSystem-v3-ActCode.html#v3-ActCode-HIVAIDS">HIVAIDS</a></td><td>HIV-AIDS program</td><td><div><p><strong>Definition:</strong> Government administered and funded HIV-AIDS program for beneficiaries meeting financial and health status criteria. Administration, funding levels, eligibility criteria, covered benefits, provider types, and financial participation are typically set by a regulatory process. Payer responsibilities for administering the program may be delegated to contractors.</p>
<p><strong>Example:</strong> In the U.S., the Ryan White program, which is administered by the Health Resources and Services Administration.</p>
</div></td></tr><tr><td><a name="R5-v3-ActProgramTypeCode-for-R4-http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode-IND"> </a><code>http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode</code></td><td>8.0.0</td><td style="white-space:nowrap">  <a href="CodeSystem-v3-ActCode.html#v3-ActCode-IND">IND</a></td><td>indigenous peoples health program</td><td><div><p><strong>Definition:</strong> Services provided directly and through contracted and operated indigenous peoples health programs.</p>
<p><strong>Example:</strong> Indian Health Service in the U.S.</p>
</div></td></tr><tr><td><a name="R5-v3-ActProgramTypeCode-for-R4-http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode-MANDPOL"> </a><code>http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode</code></td><td>8.0.0</td><td style="white-space:nowrap">  <a href="CodeSystem-v3-ActCode.html#v3-ActCode-MANDPOL">MANDPOL</a></td><td>mandatory health program</td><td><div/></td></tr><tr><td><a name="R5-v3-ActProgramTypeCode-for-R4-http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode-MENTPRG"> </a><code>http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode</code></td><td>8.0.0</td><td style="white-space:nowrap">  <a href="CodeSystem-v3-ActCode.html#v3-ActCode-MENTPRG">MENTPRG</a></td><td>mental health program</td><td><div><p><strong>Definition:</strong> Government administered and funded mental health program for beneficiaries meeting financial and mental health status criteria. Administration, funding levels, eligibility criteria, covered benefits, provider types, and financial participation are typically set by a regulatory process. Payer responsibilities for administering the program may be delegated to contractors.</p>
<p><strong>Example:</strong> In the U.S., states receive funding for substance use programs from the Substance Abuse Mental Health Administration (SAMHSA).</p>
</div></td></tr><tr><td><a name="R5-v3-ActProgramTypeCode-for-R4-http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode-MILITARY"> </a><code>http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode</code></td><td>8.0.0</td><td style="white-space:nowrap">  <a href="CodeSystem-v3-ActCode.html#v3-ActCode-MILITARY">MILITARY</a></td><td>military health program</td><td><div><p><strong>Definition:</strong> A government program that provides coverage for health services to military personnel, retirees, and dependents. A covered party who is a subscriber can choose from among Fee-for-Service (FFS) plans, and their Preferred Provider Organizations (PPO), or Plans offering a Point of Service (POS) Product, or Health Maintenance Organizations.</p>
<p><strong>Example:</strong> In the U.S., TRICARE, CHAMPUS.</p>
</div></td></tr><tr><td><a name="R5-v3-ActProgramTypeCode-for-R4-http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode-PUBLICPOL"> </a><code>http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode</code></td><td>8.0.0</td><td style="white-space:nowrap">  <a href="CodeSystem-v3-ActCode.html#v3-ActCode-PUBLICPOL">PUBLICPOL</a></td><td>public healthcare</td><td><div><p>Insurance policy funded by a public health system such as a provincial or national health plan. Examples include BC MSP (British Columbia Medical Services Plan) OHIP (Ontario Health Insurance Plan), NHS (National Health Service).</p>
</div></td></tr><tr><td><a name="R5-v3-ActProgramTypeCode-for-R4-http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode-RETIRE"> </a><code>http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode</code></td><td>8.0.0</td><td style="white-space:nowrap">  <a href="CodeSystem-v3-ActCode.html#v3-ActCode-RETIRE">RETIRE</a></td><td>retiree health program</td><td><div><p><strong>Definition:</strong> A government mandated program with specific eligibility requirements based on premium contributions made during employment, length of employment, age, and employment status, e.g., being retired, disabled, or a dependent of a covered party under this program. Benefits typically include ambulatory, inpatient, and long-term care, such as hospice care, home health care and respite care.</p>
</div></td></tr><tr><td><a name="R5-v3-ActProgramTypeCode-for-R4-http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode-SAFNET"> </a><code>http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode</code></td><td>8.0.0</td><td style="white-space:nowrap">  <a href="CodeSystem-v3-ActCode.html#v3-ActCode-SAFNET">SAFNET</a></td><td>safety net clinic program</td><td><div><p><strong>Definition:</strong> Government administered and funded program to support provision of care to underserved populations through safety net clinics.</p>
<p><strong>Example:</strong> In the U.S., safety net providers such as federally qualified health centers (FQHC) receive funding under PHSA Section 330 grants administered by the Health Resources and Services Administration.</p>
</div></td></tr><tr><td><a name="R5-v3-ActProgramTypeCode-for-R4-http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode-SOCIAL"> </a><code>http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode</code></td><td>8.0.0</td><td style="white-space:nowrap">  <a href="CodeSystem-v3-ActCode.html#v3-ActCode-SOCIAL">SOCIAL</a></td><td>social service program</td><td><div><p><strong>Definition:</strong> A social service program funded by a public or governmental entity.</p>
<p><strong>Example:</strong> Programs providing habilitation, food, lodging, medicine, transportation, equipment, devices, products, education, training, counseling, alteration of living or work space, and other resources to persons meeting eligibility criteria.</p>
</div></td></tr><tr><td><a name="R5-v3-ActProgramTypeCode-for-R4-http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode-SUBPRG"> </a><code>http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode</code></td><td>8.0.0</td><td style="white-space:nowrap">  <a href="CodeSystem-v3-ActCode.html#v3-ActCode-SUBPRG">SUBPRG</a></td><td>substance use program</td><td><div><p><strong>Definition:</strong> Government administered and funded substance use program for beneficiaries meeting financial, substance use behavior, and health status criteria. Beneficiaries may be required to enroll as a result of legal proceedings. Administration, funding levels, eligibility criteria, covered benefits, provider types, and financial participation are typically set by a regulatory process. Payer responsibilities for administering the program may be delegated to contractors.</p>
<p><strong>Example:</strong> In the U.S., states receive funding for substance use programs from the Substance Abuse Mental Health Administration (SAMHSA).</p>
</div></td></tr><tr><td><a name="R5-v3-ActProgramTypeCode-for-R4-http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode-SUBSIDIZ"> </a><code>http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode</code></td><td>8.0.0</td><td style="white-space:nowrap">  <a href="CodeSystem-v3-ActCode.html#v3-ActCode-SUBSIDIZ">SUBSIDIZ</a></td><td>subsidized health program</td><td><div><p><strong>Definition:</strong> A government health program that provides coverage for health services to persons meeting eligibility criteria such as income, location of residence, access to other coverages, health condition, and age, the cost of which is to some extent subsidized by public funds.</p>
</div></td></tr><tr><td><a name="R5-v3-ActProgramTypeCode-for-R4-http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode-SUBSIDMC"> </a><code>http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode</code></td><td>8.0.0</td><td style="white-space:nowrap">  <a href="CodeSystem-v3-ActCode.html#v3-ActCode-SUBSIDMC">SUBSIDMC</a></td><td>subsidized managed care program</td><td><div><p><strong>Definition:</strong> A government health program that provides coverage through managed care contracts for health services to persons meeting eligibility criteria such as income, location of residence, access to other coverages, health condition, and age, the cost of which is to some extent subsidized by public funds.</p>
<p><em>Discussion:</em> The structure and business processes for underwriting and administering a subsidized managed care program is further specified by the Underwriter and Payer Role.class and Role.code.</p>
</div></td></tr><tr><td><a name="R5-v3-ActProgramTypeCode-for-R4-http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode-SUBSUPP"> </a><code>http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode</code></td><td>8.0.0</td><td style="white-space:nowrap">  <a href="CodeSystem-v3-ActCode.html#v3-ActCode-SUBSUPP">SUBSUPP</a></td><td>subsidized supplemental health program</td><td><div><p><strong>Definition:</strong> A government health program that provides coverage for health services to persons meeting eligibility criteria for a supplemental health policy or program such as income, location of residence, access to other coverages, health condition, and age, the cost of which is to some extent subsidized by public funds.</p>
<p><strong>Example:</strong> Supplemental health coverage program may cover the cost of a health program or policy financial participations, such as the copays and the premiums, and may provide coverage for services in addition to those covered under the supplemented health program or policy. In the U.S., Medicaid programs may pay the premium for a covered party who is also covered under the Medicare program or a private health policy.</p>
<p><em>Discussion:</em> The structure and business processes for underwriting and administering a subsidized supplemental retiree health program is further specified by the Underwriter and Payer Role.class and Role.code.</p>
</div></td></tr><tr><td><a name="R5-v3-ActProgramTypeCode-for-R4-http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode-VET"> </a><code>http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode</code></td><td>8.0.0</td><td style="white-space:nowrap">  <a href="CodeSystem-v3-ActCode.html#v3-ActCode-VET">VET</a></td><td>veteran health program</td><td><div><p><strong>Definition:</strong> Services provided directly and through contracted and operated veteran health programs.</p>
</div></td></tr><tr><td><a name="R5-v3-ActProgramTypeCode-for-R4-http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode-WCBPOL"> </a><code>http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode</code></td><td>8.0.0</td><td style="white-space:nowrap">  <a href="CodeSystem-v3-ActCode.html#v3-ActCode-WCBPOL">WCBPOL</a></td><td>worker's compensation</td><td><div><p>Insurance policy for injuries sustained in the work place or in the course of employment.</p>
</div></td></tr><tr><td><a name="R5-v3-ActProgramTypeCode-for-R4-http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode-_ActProgramTypeCode"> </a><code>http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode</code></td><td>8.0.0</td><td style="white-space:nowrap">  <a href="CodeSystem-v3-ActCode.html#v3-ActCode-_ActProgramTypeCode">_ActProgramTypeCode</a></td><td>ActProgramTypeCode</td><td><div><p><strong>Definition:</strong> A set of codes used to indicate coverage under a program. A program is an organized structure for administering and funding coverage of a benefit package for covered parties meeting eligibility criteria, typically related to employment, health, financial, and demographic status. Programs are typically established or permitted by legislation with provisions for ongoing government oversight. Regulations may mandate the structure of the program, the manner in which it is funded and administered, covered benefits, provider types, eligibility criteria and financial participation. A government agency may be charged with implementing the program in accordance to the regulation. Risk of loss under a program in most cases would not meet what an underwriter would consider an insurable risk, i.e., the risk is not random in nature, not financially measurable, and likely requires subsidization with government funds.</p>
<p><em>Discussion:</em> Programs do not have policy holders or subscribers. Program eligibles are enrolled based on health status, statutory eligibility, financial status, or age. Program eligibles who are covered parties under the program may be referred to as members, beneficiaries, eligibles, or recipients. Programs risk are underwritten by not for profit organizations such as governmental entities, and the beneficiaries typically do not pay for any or some portion of the cost of coverage. See CoveredPartyRoleType.</p>
</div></td></tr></table></div>
  </text>
  <extension url="http://hl7.org/fhir/StructureDefinition/structuredefinition-wg">
    <valueCode value="fhir"/>
  </extension>
  <extension url="http://hl7.org/fhir/StructureDefinition/package-source">
    <extension url="packageId">
      <valueId value="hl7.fhir.uv.xver-r5.r4"/>
    </extension>
    <extension url="version">
      <valueString value="0.0.1-snapshot-3"/>
    </extension>
    <extension url="uri">
      <valueUri value="http://hl7.org/fhir/uv/xver/ImplementationGuide/hl7.fhir.uv.xver-r5.r4"/>
    </extension>
  </extension>
  <extension url="http://hl7.org/fhir/StructureDefinition/structuredefinition-fmm">
    <valueInteger value="0">
      <extension url="http://hl7.org/fhir/StructureDefinition/structuredefinition-conformance-derivedFrom">
        <valueCanonical value="http://hl7.org/fhir/uv/xver/ImplementationGuide/hl7.fhir.uv.xver-r5.r4"/>
      </extension>
    </valueInteger>
  </extension>
  <extension url="http://hl7.org/fhir/StructureDefinition/structuredefinition-standards-status">
    <valueCode value="trial-use">
      <extension url="http://hl7.org/fhir/StructureDefinition/structuredefinition-conformance-derivedFrom">
        <valueCanonical value="http://hl7.org/fhir/uv/xver/ImplementationGuide/hl7.fhir.uv.xver-r5.r4"/>
      </extension>
    </valueCode>
  </extension>
  <url value="http://hl7.org/fhir/uv/xver/ValueSet/R5-v3-ActProgramTypeCode-for-R4"/>
  <version value="0.0.1-snapshot-3"/>
  <name value="R5V3ActProgramTypeCodeForR4"/>
  <title value="Cross-version ValueSet R5.ActProgramTypeCode for use in FHIR R4"/>
  <status value="active"/>
  <experimental value="false"/>
  <date value="2026-02-21T19:36:42.9229177+00:00"/>
  <publisher value="FHIR Infrastructure"/>
  <contact>
    <name value="FHIR Infrastructure"/>
    <telecom>
      <system value="url"/>
      <value value="http://www.hl7.org/Special/committees/fiwg"/>
    </telecom>
  </contact>
  <description value="This cross-version ValueSet represents content from `http://terminology.hl7.org/ValueSet/v3-ActProgramTypeCode|2.0.0` for use in FHIR R4."/>
  <jurisdiction>
    <coding>
      <system value="http://unstats.un.org/unsd/methods/m49/m49.htm"/>
      <code value="001"/>
      <display value="World"/>
    </coding>
  </jurisdiction>
  <purpose value="This value set is part of the cross-version definitions generated to enable use of the&#xD;&#xA;value set `http://terminology.hl7.org/ValueSet/v3-ActProgramTypeCode|2.0.0` as defined in FHIR R5&#xD;&#xA;in FHIR R4.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;The source value set is bound to the following FHIR R5 elements:&#xD;&#xA;* &#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;The following concepts are not included in this cross-version definition because they have valid representations&#xD;&#xA;* _no concepts_&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;Following are the generation technical comments:&#xD;&#xA;&#xA;FHIR ValueSet `http://terminology.hl7.org/ValueSet/v3-ActProgramTypeCode|2.0.0`, defined in FHIR R5 does not have any mapping to FHIR R4"/>
  <compose>
    <include>
      <system value="http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode"/>
      <version value="8.0.0"/>
      <concept>
        <code value="CANPRG"/>
        <display value="women's cancer detection program"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="CHAR"/>
        <display value="charity program"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="CRIME"/>
        <display value="crime victim program"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="DENTPRG"/>
        <display value="dental program"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="DISEASEPRG"/>
        <display value="public health program"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="EAP"/>
        <display value="employee assistance program"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="ENDRENAL"/>
        <display value="end renal program"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="GOVEMP"/>
        <display value="government employee health program"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="HIRISK"/>
        <display value="high risk pool program"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="HIVAIDS"/>
        <display value="HIV-AIDS program"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="IND"/>
        <display value="indigenous peoples health program"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="MANDPOL"/>
        <display value="mandatory health program"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="MENTPRG"/>
        <display value="mental health program"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="MILITARY"/>
        <display value="military health program"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="PUBLICPOL"/>
        <display value="public healthcare"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="RETIRE"/>
        <display value="retiree health program"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="SAFNET"/>
        <display value="safety net clinic program"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="SOCIAL"/>
        <display value="social service program"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="SUBPRG"/>
        <display value="substance use program"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="SUBSIDIZ"/>
        <display value="subsidized health program"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="SUBSIDMC"/>
        <display value="subsidized managed care program"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="SUBSUPP"/>
        <display value="subsidized supplemental health program"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="VET"/>
        <display value="veteran health program"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="WCBPOL"/>
        <display value="worker's compensation"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="_ActProgramTypeCode"/>
        <display value="ActProgramTypeCode"/>
      </concept>
    </include>
  </compose>
  <expansion>
    <timestamp value="2026-02-21T19:36:42.9229177+00:00"/>
    <contains>
      <system value="http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode"/>
      <version value="8.0.0"/>
      <code value="CANPRG"/>
      <display value="women's cancer detection program"/>
    </contains>
    <contains>
      <system value="http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode"/>
      <version value="8.0.0"/>
      <code value="CHAR"/>
      <display value="charity program"/>
    </contains>
    <contains>
      <system value="http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode"/>
      <version value="8.0.0"/>
      <code value="CRIME"/>
      <display value="crime victim program"/>
    </contains>
    <contains>
      <system value="http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode"/>
      <version value="8.0.0"/>
      <code value="DENTPRG"/>
      <display value="dental program"/>
    </contains>
    <contains>
      <system value="http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode"/>
      <version value="8.0.0"/>
      <code value="DISEASEPRG"/>
      <display value="public health program"/>
    </contains>
    <contains>
      <system value="http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode"/>
      <version value="8.0.0"/>
      <code value="EAP"/>
      <display value="employee assistance program"/>
    </contains>
    <contains>
      <system value="http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode"/>
      <version value="8.0.0"/>
      <code value="ENDRENAL"/>
      <display value="end renal program"/>
    </contains>
    <contains>
      <system value="http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode"/>
      <version value="8.0.0"/>
      <code value="GOVEMP"/>
      <display value="government employee health program"/>
    </contains>
    <contains>
      <system value="http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode"/>
      <version value="8.0.0"/>
      <code value="HIRISK"/>
      <display value="high risk pool program"/>
    </contains>
    <contains>
      <system value="http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode"/>
      <version value="8.0.0"/>
      <code value="HIVAIDS"/>
      <display value="HIV-AIDS program"/>
    </contains>
    <contains>
      <system value="http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode"/>
      <version value="8.0.0"/>
      <code value="IND"/>
      <display value="indigenous peoples health program"/>
    </contains>
    <contains>
      <system value="http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode"/>
      <version value="8.0.0"/>
      <code value="MANDPOL"/>
      <display value="mandatory health program"/>
    </contains>
    <contains>
      <system value="http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode"/>
      <version value="8.0.0"/>
      <code value="MENTPRG"/>
      <display value="mental health program"/>
    </contains>
    <contains>
      <system value="http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode"/>
      <version value="8.0.0"/>
      <code value="MILITARY"/>
      <display value="military health program"/>
    </contains>
    <contains>
      <system value="http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode"/>
      <version value="8.0.0"/>
      <code value="PUBLICPOL"/>
      <display value="public healthcare"/>
    </contains>
    <contains>
      <system value="http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode"/>
      <version value="8.0.0"/>
      <code value="RETIRE"/>
      <display value="retiree health program"/>
    </contains>
    <contains>
      <system value="http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode"/>
      <version value="8.0.0"/>
      <code value="SAFNET"/>
      <display value="safety net clinic program"/>
    </contains>
    <contains>
      <system value="http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode"/>
      <version value="8.0.0"/>
      <code value="SOCIAL"/>
      <display value="social service program"/>
    </contains>
    <contains>
      <system value="http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode"/>
      <version value="8.0.0"/>
      <code value="SUBPRG"/>
      <display value="substance use program"/>
    </contains>
    <contains>
      <system value="http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode"/>
      <version value="8.0.0"/>
      <code value="SUBSIDIZ"/>
      <display value="subsidized health program"/>
    </contains>
    <contains>
      <system value="http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode"/>
      <version value="8.0.0"/>
      <code value="SUBSIDMC"/>
      <display value="subsidized managed care program"/>
    </contains>
    <contains>
      <system value="http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode"/>
      <version value="8.0.0"/>
      <code value="SUBSUPP"/>
      <display value="subsidized supplemental health program"/>
    </contains>
    <contains>
      <system value="http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode"/>
      <version value="8.0.0"/>
      <code value="VET"/>
      <display value="veteran health program"/>
    </contains>
    <contains>
      <system value="http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode"/>
      <version value="8.0.0"/>
      <code value="WCBPOL"/>
      <display value="worker's compensation"/>
    </contains>
    <contains>
      <system value="http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActCode"/>
      <version value="8.0.0"/>
      <code value="_ActProgramTypeCode"/>
      <display value="ActProgramTypeCode"/>
    </contains>
  </expansion>
</ValueSet>